Hi, this is John Stewart and this is how to pack your tent poles for a weekend camping trip.
You don't want to take and roll up your tent poles with your tent because it takes up a lot of room.
So you're going to pack and stuff down your tent and put it on the inside of your pack.
Since your tent poles are normally longer than the inside of your pack, you always want to take and put these on the outside of the pack.
You can strap these right on the outside.
They don't have to worry about getting them wet because you'll have a pack cover on.
That way they're outside, real quick to get to when you set up your tent in the afternoon.
And they don't get in the way.
The other nice thing about this is you can strap them down nice and tight to where they don't rattle and make a lot of racket while you're out there packing.
So most packs are going to have sleeves on the outside of the pack to where you can just slide your tent poles right down on the sleeves, get it all the way to the bottom and then you just take and cinch down the straps to where your tent poles won't move on the outside of your pack.
They lay nice and flat against the pack, and you don't have to worry about them going anywhere cause they're not going to fall out the bottom of the pack.
This is how to pack your tent poles for a weekend camping trip.